Guide to the Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region collection, 1973-1992 MS2160
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region collection
1973-1992
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2160
1.75 Linear Feet
Collection contains programs, flyers, clippings, audiocassettes, reel-to-reel audiotapes, film, and published materials. The material dates from 1973 to 1992. This is an artificial collection on the subject of dance.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
[required]
Historical Note
The Dance Archives of the Greater Washington Region was established in 1992 to preserve and make available dance artifacts evolving from the dance related activities of individuals and organizations in the Greater Washington Metropolitan region.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains programs, flyers, clippings, audiocassettes, reel-to-reel audiotapes, film, and published materials. The material dates from 1973 to 1992. This is an artificial collection on the subject of dance. The materials are divided into series based on the individual who donated them.
Collection Organization
The collection is organized into four series: Masters accretion, Deal accretion, Grut accretion, and Unidentified donor accretion.
Dancers; Dance; Moving images; Audiotapes; Audiocassettes; Washington (D.C.); Grut, Marina; Deal, Melvin; Masters, Deborah C.
- Masters Accretion, 1988-1993; MS2160 Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains programs, flyers, and clippings related to dance and dance concerts in the Washington, D.C. area. The materials date from 1988-93. The materials were donated by Deborah C. Masters, former University Librarian of Gelman Library, The George Washington University.
  - Programs, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
  - Programs, invitation, newsletter, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, flyers, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Deal Accretion, undated; MS2160 Series 2; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of one VHS videotape donated by Melvin Deal, a dancer specializing in African dance. The videotape is undated.
  - VHS: Current Amiv [?], undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Grut Accretion, 1973-1992; MS2160 Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 3, Box 4)
  This series consists of published materials, reel-to-reel tapes, and audio cassette tapes. The material dates from 1973-92. The material was donated by Marina Keet Grut, an expert in Spanish dance and former lecturer in Dance at The George Washington University.
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: CORD Conference Martha Davis presentation, 06/13/1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 1 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 2 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 3 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 4 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 5 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 6 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 7 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual materials: Reel-to-reel: Tape number 8 of Research in Dance Workshop, 10/14/1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Audio-visual materials: Audiocassettes: unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Audio-visual materials: Film: unidentified, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Published materials: "The Spanish Dance" by Marina Keet, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Published materials: Escuela Bolera, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Unidentified donor accretion, 1985-1994; MS2160 Series 4; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 5)
  This series contains newsletters, minutes, mailings, reports, promotional materials records (sound recordings), and other materials related to dance and dance organizations in the Washington, D.C. area. The materials date from 1985-94. The series includes materials created by individual dance companies as well as organizations which support dance and the performing arts.
  - Committee to Save Dance in Washington, 1985 ca. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Open meeting of the dance community minutes, 03/1986-04/1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Coalition of Washington Artists, 05/1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan Dance Association, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New Dance Place, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Performing Arts Archives--workshop materials, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Images of American Dance: Documenting and Preserving a Cultural Heritage, 1990 ca. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dance Exchange, 1993 ca. --1994 ca. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Interview with Martha Graham, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)